Guide to the Office of the Director of Research and of the Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station records,1935-1964.
Office of the Director of Research and of the Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station Records, 1935-1965}
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Office of the Director of Research and of the Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station records, 1935-1964.
21-12-829
New York State College of Agriculture.Office of the Director of Research and of the Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station
5 cubic ft.
Reports, Research Materials, Publications, Correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subject files, correspondence, and other papers of the office.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subject files, correspondence, and other papers of the office.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture.; Cornell University--Administration.
Subjects:
Agricultural experiment stations--New York (State); Agriculture--Research--New York (State)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Subject Files, Research Programs, Federal Programs
  - Proposed Budget For INcrease in FY 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committee of Three, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Committee of Nine, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of the Committee of Nine, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Corn Improvement Conference, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, Interregional and National Coordinating Committees, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General-Regional Research, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - USDA Publications, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Utilization-American Farm Bureau Project, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Proposed Regional Communications Project, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Proposed Forage Disease Project, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pennsylvania State University-Dept. of Agricultural Education, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cornell University Evaluation Study, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Middle Atlantic States Report, 1951-1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "An Evaluation of the Aims and Affairs of Pennsylvania State University", November 6-8, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Pennsylvania State University-Report to the Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - New York State Temporary Commission on Agriculture, October 14-15, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - New York State Temporary Commission on Agriculture, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Report to USDA-Examples of Research Results, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Support of Research, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - New Projects, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Requests for Increased Funds from Departments, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - RRF Lapses in Funds, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Proposed Regional Projects, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Regional Research Policy at Cornell, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Research Advisory Committees, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Adams Numbers, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Research Data, 1940-1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bankhead-Jones Research Project Numbers, 1936-37 to 1955-56 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bank-head Requests, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Purnell Research Project Numbers, 1936-37 to 1955-56 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Federal Assignments and Reserves in Director's Office, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Federal Assignments and Reserves in Director's Office, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Federal Research Program, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Federal Research Program, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Federal Research Program, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Research and Marketing Fund-Flanagan-Hope Research Program, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Research and Marketing Project Numbers, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Research and Marketing-Title II Projects, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Research and Marketing Assignments and Reserves in Director's Office, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Federal Assignments and Reserves in Director's Office (Including Research and Marketing Assignments), 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Federal Assignments and Reserves in Director's Office (Including Research and Marketing Assignments), 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Federal Assignments and Reserves in Director Guterman's Office (Including Research and Marketing Assignments), 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Federal Assignments and Reserves in Director Guterman's Office (Including Research and Marketing Assignments), 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Federal Assignments and Reserves in Director Guterman's Office (Including Research and Marketing Assignments), 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Research and Marketing, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Research and Marketing Program, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Research and Marketing Program, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Research and Marketing Program, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Federal Research Program-Hatch, Adams, Purnell, Bankhead-Jones, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Federal Research Program-Hatch, Adams, Purnell, Bankhead-Jones, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Federal Research Program-Hatch, Adams, Purnell, Bankhead-Jones, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Examples of Research for Use by Dean Myer; Also Summary of NIH & NSF Support (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Mimeographed Reports on Research Projects in Agriculture, 1935-1958 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Agriculture Aviation Conference-Questionnaire, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Aircraft Dusters Conference, Notes, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Research and Marketing Program, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Research and Marketing Program, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Research and Marketing Program, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Federal Research Program-Hatch, Adams, Purnell, Bankhead-Jones, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Federal Research Program-Hatch, Adams, Purnell, Bankhead-Jones, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Federal Research Program-Hatch, Adams, Purnell, Bankhead-Jones, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Federal Assignments and Reserves in Director Guterman's Office,Including Research and Marketing Assignments, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Pennsylvania State University Evaluating Team, 1949-1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Requests for Information on Outstanding Research, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series II: Projects, Department Head Meeting Minutes, Committee Meeting Minutes
  - Director's Hatch Reserve, July 1, 1961-June 30, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Department Head Meetings, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Deparment Heads Dinner Meeting (Sun Room, Statler Hall), February 2, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Department Heads Dinner Meeting (Elmhirst Room, Willard Straight Hall), April 11, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Department Heads Dinner Meeting (Elmhirst Room, Willard Straight Hall), September 19, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Department Heads Dinner Meeting (Elmhirst Room, Willard Straight Hall), February 6, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Department Heads Dinner Meeting (Elmhirst Room, Willard Straight Hall), May 9, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Department Heads Dinner Meeting (Elmhirst Room, Willard Straight Hall), October 23, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Faculty Research Grants Committee-Dr. Palm Asked to serve on Committee in Letter of May 9, 1957 from Dean John W. McConnell of the Graduate School (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Faculty Research Grants Committee, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - AG Faculty-Ad Hoc Committee-Meeting Minutes, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - University Faculty-Meeting Minutes, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - College Seed Committee-Meeting Minutes, 1947-1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - College Seed Committee-Meeting Minutes, 1951-1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - College Seed Committee-Meeting Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Irrigation Committee, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Irrigation Committee, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Irrigation Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Irrigation Sub-Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Publications Committee-College of Agriculture, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Publications Committee-Proceedings of Annual Meeting, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - New York Agricultural and Conservation Council, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - New York Agricultural and Conservation Council, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - New York Agricultural and Conservation Council, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Administration, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - New York State Temporary Commission of Agriculture, October 14-15, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Agricultural Institutes, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Agricultural Research Institute, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Agrisearch Newsletter, 1955-1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Annual Call Letters, 1954-1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - J.M. McDonald Farm, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Council for the New York State Veterinary College, Minutes of the Meeting, January 3, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Motion Picture Committee, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - National Academy of Sciences-National Research Council, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - New York State Agricultural Society, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Northeast Farm Management Research Committee, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Photo Clippings, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Plant Patents, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Programs, Pamphlets, etc., 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Publications, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Research and Extension Program for Western New York-St. Lawrence Substation (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Articles and Speeches-R.L. Plaisted, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Biochemistry and Nutrition (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bulletin Requests, etc., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Catalogue of USDA Forms, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Dean's Report to the President, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Department Heads-Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Expenditure of Funds by Month and Departments, April-June 1956 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Departmental Plots-Field-Correspondence, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Office of Foreign Visitors, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Time Distribution of Professional Workers-Survey of Official Activities and Reseach Activities, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - USDA Council Meeting, December 20, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - USDA Council-NY-US;Agriculture Council-Meeting Minutes, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - NY-US-USDA Meeting Reports, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Grant Research Reviews, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Honey Unit Methods, March 14th, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Committee on Liberty Hyde Bailey Centennial Celebration, March 14, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - NSF Form #874-Scientific Activities in State Agricultural Experiment Stations, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Summary Report-Hay Research, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - W.I. Meyers - E. Stuart Hubbard - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Summary Report of the Directors Conference of Research Museums of Natural History, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - New York Nursery Notes-1958-1959; 1959 Convention of Eastern Nurserymen-Program and Directory (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - New York State Soil Conservation Committee-Meeting Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Northeastern Directors-Fall Meeting, Washington, DC, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Northeastern Experimental Stations-Directors' Meeting-Minutes, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Northeastern Directors-Spring Meeting, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Northeastern Experiment Station Directors' Meeting, Notes and Correspondence, Spring 1959 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Northeastern Agricultural Experiment Stations, Meeting Mintutes and Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Northeastern Agricultural Experiment Stations, Meeting minutes and Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - NE Directors Spring Meeting at Wilmington, Delaware, March 8-9, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Soil and Water Conservation Inventory, August 2, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Soil and Water Conservation Reseach Facility Needs, November 17, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - State Experiment Stations Division, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - New York State Agricultural Society-Conferences and Annual Meetings, 1952-1959 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Material for Editing=Proposed Budget- New York State College of Agriculture, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Pennsylvania State University Evaluation, November 6-9, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Non-Federal Fund Expenditures for Research Fiscal Year Ending June 30, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Requests for Additional Hatch Funds for Fiscal Year 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Areas of Research Needing Support in Connection with Budget Requests for 1960 (Legislative Committee Request), 1958 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Budget Figures and Finances-Report to SESD for Budget Requests for 1959, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Advisory Committee on the Research and Marketing Act, 1948-1951 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Summer Meeting-NE Directors at Kingston, Rhode Island, July 14-17, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Spring Meeting-NE Directors, March 10-11, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Northeastern Directors-Meeting Minutes, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Soil Survey Resolution, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - ESCOP Legislative Committee-Heads of Departments-Letters on Increased Hatch Amended Funds for Federal Fiscal Year 1956 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Special Report to the State University, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - National Canners Association, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Proposed Inter-Regional Research Project in Agricultural Price Policy, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Regional and Inter-Regional Projects, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Series III: Correspondence, 1946-1964
  - Office of the Dean-Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Agricultural Situation and Outlook, December, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Agricultural Economics-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Agricultural Economics-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Agricultural Engineering-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural Engineering Advisory Committee-Meeting Minutes, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Agronomy-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Agronomy-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Annual GLF-Agronomy Research Report, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Livestock Advisory Council-Meeting Minutes, May 1, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Animal Husbandry-Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Animal Husbandry-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Animal Husbandry-GLF Review, May, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Bailey Hortorium-"Baileygram"-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Biochemistry-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Business Office-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Botony-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Conservation-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Dairy and Food Science-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Entomology and Limnology-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Extension-Office of Director and Associate Director-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Extension-State Leaders Office=Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Extension-Teaching and Information-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Extension-Miscellaneous-Correspondence, Reports, Plans of Work, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Farm Services-"Farm Experience of Men Students at the Time of Entrance to the New York State College of Agriculture-Cornell University"-October 4, 1961, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - GLF Plant Breeding Research Grants-1958 Report; Conference-April 9, 1959, 1958, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - GLF Plant Breeding Research Grants-1960 Report; Conference-April 11, 1961, 1960, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - GLF Plant Breeding Research Conference-Hybrid Corn Field Trials, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - GLF Forage Program, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Plant Breeding-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Home Economics-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Home Economics-Correspondence; Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Plant Pathology-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Pomology-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Poultry Husbandry-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Resident Instruction-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Rural Education-Correspondence; Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Rural Sociology-Correspondence; Bulletins, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Vegetable Crops-Correspondence; Budgets; etc., 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Land for Vegetable Crops Research-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Veterinary College-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - A-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC)-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Agricultural Experiment Station, Geneva, New York-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - American Cynamid Company Dinner Meeting-Correspondence, Brochures, December 20, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - B-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - C-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - D-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Driver, P.N.-Biographical Sketch, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - E-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - F-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Fruit Virus Indexing (Plant Pathology-Ithaca and Geneva)-Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Fulbright Award and Fellowships-Letters Written on Cornell Staff Members), 1951-1959 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - G-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - GLF-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Gruman Aircraft Engineering Corporation-Joe Lippert-Correspondence, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - H-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Hotels-Correspondence, 1951-1961 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - I-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - J-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Johnson, Allen-Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - K-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - L-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Lemon, Edgar R.-Correspondence, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Lowe, John-Correspondence, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - M-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Meterology Lecture-Correspondence, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - N-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - National Science Foundation-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - National Science Foundation Proposal, Summer Program-Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - News Releases-From NYS College of Agriculture, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - NE Small Grains Survey-Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - P-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Patent Policy-Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Patent Policy-Correspondence, 1948-1958 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Physiology, Field of-Memorandum and Meeting Minutes, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Vice President's Office and Coordinator of Research-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Questionnaires-Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - R-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Rovetch, Warren-Correspondence, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - S-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - SESD-Federal Research Program, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - SESD-Experiment Station Letters #605-#654 (Pink Sheets) (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - T-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Teaching Machines-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - U-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - USDA-Miscellaneous Departments and Divisions, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - USDA-Miscellaneous Departments and Divisions, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - USDA-State Experiment Station Division-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - V-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Vice President's Office and Coordniator of Research-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - W-Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 59)